let's start without further although I'm
让我们开始吧，尽管我
gonna show you some basics around ARCA
将向您展示有关ARCA的一些基础知识
actors and I'm gonna show you some of
演员，我要给你看一些
the new eight the ice that we introduced
我们介绍的新八块冰
in in ARCA for Java 8 specifically I
在ARCA for Java 8中
will start with introducing myself so my
从介绍自己开始，所以我的
name is u1 and Riaan and I'm a developer
名字是u1和Riaan，我是一名开发人员
out of Stockholm Sweden I work for a
我在瑞典斯德哥尔摩工作
light band in the in the akka core team
Akka核心团队中的乐队
before joining Lichtman I worked on
在加入Lichtman之前，我曾在
consulting and mentoring around Scala
Scala的咨询和指导
and akka and play framework and before
和akka和play框架以及之前
that I have quite a bit of experience on
我有很多经验
the Java platform so that is about me
Java平台，这就是关于我的
before I start talking about
在我开始谈论之前
specifically I'm going to talk a bit
我特别要说一点
about the background or what I see as
关于背景或我所看到的
some very good reasons that akka is
Akka的一些很好的理由
useful and maybe also some of the
有用的，也许还有一些
reasons that I came into existence since
我之所以存在的原因
the dawn of computers the processors
电脑处理器的曙光
clock speeds has basically increased and
时钟速度已基本提高，
increased and increased so every year
每年都在增加
that single-threaded program I wrote
我写的那个单线程程序
last year was faster and this was true
去年更快，这是事实
up till the point around maybe 2005 as
直到大约2005年为止
you can see here in this graph it done
您可以在此图中看到它完成
kind of leveled out so what happened at
有点变平了，所以发生了什么
that point well we got to this point
那一点好，我们到了这一点
where it's not energy efficient or
能源效率不高的地方
practical to keep making the clock
保持时钟实用
cycles shorter and shorter so
周期越来越短，所以
the processor makers then started to
然后，处理器制造商开始
create CPUs with more cores of course we
当然，我们创建具有更多内核的CPU
had this nice free lunch before where
在哪里吃过这个免费的午餐
our programs just got faster and faster
我们的程序越来越快
or we could be lazier and lazier as
否则我们可能会变得越来越懒惰
programmers and our programs but anyways
程序员和我们的程序，但无论如何
run very swiftly but at this point we
运行非常迅速，但在这一点上，我们
can't really get this kind of speed
真的不能达到这样的速度
improvements for free anymore so we have
免费改进了，所以我们有
to start writing programs using threads
开始使用线程编写程序
and just so we would have to structure
只是这样，我们将不得不结构
our programs differently and we would
我们的程序有所不同，我们会
have to start using threading primitives
必须开始使用线程原语
to to make use of the entire CPU world
利用整个CPU世界
to make our CPU bound processing faster
使我们的CPU绑定处理更快
so this is one thing that has happened I
所以这是我发生的一件事
would say like in in recent years even
甚至会说近年来
though it's not super recent another
虽然不是最近
thing that has changed is that a couple
改变的是一对夫妇
of years ago then a typical kind of
几年前，然后是典型的
service setup would be that's one server
服务设置将是一台服务器
and a failover maybe so we could kind of
和故障转移也许所以我们可以
save keep running our business even even
节省甚至继续经营我们的业务
though our primary would go down and we
虽然我们的小学会下降，我们
would maybe have a couple of hundred
可能有几百个
thousand users and each of those would
千名用户，每个用户
maybe have one computer each one device
每个设备可能有一台电脑
that they would access our system with
他们将通过以下方式访问我们的系统
so if we fast forward to today then this
所以如果我们快进到今天
has kind of changed so the users will be
已经有所改变，因此用户将
more you will have much more users and
更多，您将拥有更多的用户，并且
each user might have a bunch of devices
每个用户可能有一堆设备
that the XS are serviced with and their
XS的维修服务及其
expectations has also changed very much
期望也发生了很大变化
so
所以
they will maybe go to a competitor as
他们可能会去竞争对手
soon as they have to wait for maybe for
他们不得不等待也许
five seconds or their expectations of
五秒钟或他们的期望
the service always being available has
始终可用的服务有
totally changed so I would kind of state
完全改变了，所以我会有点状态
that we we need abstractions to write
我们需要抽象来编写
applications that fulfill both the need
同时满足需求的应用程序
to use a single machine better to
更好地使用一台机器来
actually make use of all those course
实际利用所有这些课程
but also to be able to build systems
而且能够建立系统
that can use more than one server in
可以使用多个服务器
simple ways or in ways that are easy to
简单的方式或易于实现的方式
reason about so back to academic is a
回到学术的原因是
tool kit to build concurrent and
建立并发和
distributed applications it's not a
分布式应用程序不是
framework which is a difference to many
框架对许多人来说是不同的
other technologies that are targeted at
针对的其他技术
the same crowd
同一群人
it's less of something that tells you
更少的东西告诉你
how to structure your system and how to
如何构建系统以及如何
build your architecture and more of a
建立您的架构以及更多
very useful tool box to pick up
拿起非常有用的工具箱
different tools from when you need to
与您需要时使用的工具不同
build a system that can scale over many
建立一个可以扩展许多规模的系统
course and many computers in this
当然还有很多电脑
toolbox we have actors which is what
我们有演员的工具箱是什么
we're going to cover today and we also
我们今天要讲，我们也
have something called akka streams and
有东西叫做阿卡溪流
we have an HTTP server and a few other
我们有一个HTTP服务器和其他一些
nice tools it is written in in Scala but
它是用Scala编写的好工具，但是
there is four for every feature there is
每个功能都有四个
also a job API so even though the
也是一个作业API，所以即使
internals are written in Scala it is
内部构件是用Scala编写的
possible to use all the parts from Java
可以使用Java的所有部分
and in this talk we will specifically
在本次演讲中，我们将专门
look at actors so we won't touch much of
看演员，所以我们不会涉及太多
the other others
其他的
in there interesting is that there is
有趣的是
also a dotnet porta baka so if you're on
还有一个dotnet porta baka，所以如果你在
the dotnet CLR you can also use a key
dotnet CLR您还可以使用一个密钥
from C sharp or the other languages I
来自C Sharp或其他语言
guess ok so actors actors was introduced
好的，所以演员介绍了演员
or proposed by a guy called
或由一个叫
call Hewitt together with Peter Bishop
与彼得·毕晓普一起给休伊特打电话
and Richard stager in 1973 so it was a
和1973年的理查德·史特雷格
academic paper about a model for
关于模型的学术论文
concurrent computation that uses actors
使用参与者的并发计算
at universal primitive of concurrent
在并发的通用原语
premutation sorry computation this was
预突变抱歉计算这是
then implemented with Erlang in 1986 I
然后在1986年与Erlang一起实施
think that's one of the more famous
认为那是更著名的之一
implementations of the actor model
角色模型的实现
except raka and then akka was founded in
除了raka然后akka成立于
2009 so you have been doing this since
2009年以来，您一直在这样做
2009 that's seven years by now so it's
2009年到现在已经七年了
by no means a young framework with that
绝不是一个年轻的框架
being said I would still claim that
有人说我仍然会声称
we're moving forward in a pretty good
我们正在向前迈进
pace so it's also not not at all
节奏，所以它也不是根本
something that is stale because of
因为
having this years behind us so what is
在我们后面有这几年，那是什么
an actor an actor is a regular an
演员演员是普通演员
instance of a regular class so you write
常规类的实例，因此您可以编写
the Reg totally regular class but there
Reg完全是普通班，但是那里
is a big difference in how you interact
互动方式有很大不同
with it and how other objects interact
与它以及其他对象如何相互作用
with it so the only way to have
有了它，所以拥有的唯一方法
communication and interact with an actor
与演员交流和互动
is through messages so to make an actor
是通过消息来使演员
do something you send it a message a
做一些事情，你给它发送一条消息
message is again also a totally you
信息再次完全是你
regular class
普通班
but it has to be immutable because we
但是它必须是不变的，因为我们
will send them across a synchronous
将通过同步发送
boundaries and as soon as we start doing
边界，我们一开始就做
that with mutable data you will have to
使用可变数据，您将不得不
synchronize them it will be back in this
同步它们，它将回到此
complicated world of threat primitives
威胁原语的复杂世界
so when an actor receives a message it
所以当演员收到消息时
can do four things it can send messages
可以做四件事，可以发送消息
to other actors it can mutate its own
对于其他演员，它可以改变自己的角色
state it can change its behavior how it
说明它可以改变其行为方式
will react on following messages and it
将对以下消息做出反应，它
can create more actors so I think this
可以创造更多的演员，所以我认为
is where we stop looking at slides and I
是我们停止看幻灯片的地方，而我
will show you some code samples of of
将向您显示的一些代码示例
actors so I have prepared this Java
演员，所以我准备了这个Java
project so first I want to show you that
项目，所以首先我想告诉你
since like as I told you that okay is to
因为就像我告诉你的那样
keep another framework there is there is
保持另一个框架存在
not like a microkernel or anything that
不像微内核或其他任何东西
you run your application on top of it's
您在它之上运行应用程序
just a regular dependency so you pull in
只是一个常规的依赖项，所以您加入
actor like this in your maven project
在您的Maven项目中像这样的演员
and then you can decide to use it in
然后您可以决定在
parts of your application or in the
您的应用程序的一部分或
build your entire application on it it's
在其上构建整个应用程序
totally up to you okay
完全取决于你
so let's let's make simple see if I can
让我们简单地看一下我是否可以
open this
打开这个
that's weird okay so we're going to
那很奇怪，所以我们要
start with I told you that an actor can
首先我告诉你演员可以
react on a message by changing its state
通过更改其状态来响应消息
so we're going to start with writing as
所以我们将开始写为
an actor that does exactly that I'm
完全符合我的演员
gonna use some tricks here that aren't
会在这里使用一些技巧
maybe what you would expect to see over
也许你希望看到的
the below
下面
partly because I don't spend all this
部分原因是我没有花所有的钱
writing Java but also partly to keep it
编写Java但也要部分保留它
short and concise and that I can show it
简短而简洁，我可以证明
in one screen so don't feel upset about
在一个屏幕上，所以不要感到沮丧
about non idiomatic Java code here so I
关于非惯用的Java代码，所以我
will start with creating a new class
从创建一个新的类开始
which is our counter and to make it an
这是我们的柜台，并使其成为
actor I'm gonna extend abstract actor
演员我要扩展抽象演员
which comes from arcade or tacular
来自街机或望远镜
package actually I'm going to extend
包，实际上我要扩展
abstract logging actor by doing that we
通过这样做我们抽象的采伐演员
will get a logger for free so we can
将免费获得记录器，因此我们可以
easily write some some output from the
轻松地从中写入一些输出
actor so the next thing we're going to
演员，接下来我们要做的是
do is to define a protocol so I told you
就是定义一个协议，所以我告诉你
that we communicate with actors through
我们通过与演员沟通
through messages so now we're going to
通过消息，所以现在我们要
define the messages or the message that
定义消息或消息
this actor will accept and this is
这个演员会接受，这是
actually the place where my kind of
其实是我那种地方
weird habits is a good idea so it's a
怪异的习惯是个好主意，所以
good idea to define your your protocol
定义协议的好主意
close too close to their class the actor
演员离他们的阶级太近了
which a protocol is for so in this case
在这种情况下，哪个协议适用
I'm going to define them inside of the
我将在内部定义它们
actor aesthetic classes
演员美学课
so I'm gonna define the class message
所以我要定义班级信息
and I'm just I'm not gonna let it have
我只是我不会让它拥有
any any kind of data inside we're just
我们里面的任何数据
gonna use it to trigger a counter that
会用它来触发一个计数器
will increase over time okay and then
会随着时间的推移增加，然后
I'm gonna define an initializer block so
我要定义一个初始化块
this is an example of where you might
这是您可能会遇到的一个例子
not what you might not do a regular java
不是您可能不会做的常规Java
code but this is just like the default
代码，但这就像默认值
constructor
建设者
so in this constructor block we'll call
因此，在此构造函数块中，我们将调用
receive and receive takes something that
接收和接收需要一些东西
is called a virtual function which is a
被称为虚函数
scholar construct so but to build one of
学者构造，但建立之一
those we have a Java API so we're going
那些我们有一个Java API，所以我们要
to use something called a receive
使用一种叫做接收的东西
builder which is like the the Builder
就像建造者
pattern and you have seen it a thousand
模式，您已经看到了一千
times before I guess in in Java land and
我猜到Java土地之前的时间和
with this receive builder we can define
有了这个接收器，我们可以定义
cases which we will react on in the
我们将在
actor so in this case we're going to say
演员，在这种情况下，我们要说
match and then we're going to say every
比赛，然后我们要说每个
time there is a message of this class
时间有这个班级的消息
call this function or this method so
调用此函数或方法
we're going to define that as method
我们将其定义为方法
handle like so and then I'm going to
这样处理，然后我要
define this method
定义这个方法
like that
像那样
in the end I also need to in the end of
最后我还需要
the Builder I need to actually build of
我需要实际构建的构建器
course like so and then I said we were
当然是这样，然后我说我们
gonna keep a new Tait State so I'm gonna
要保持一个新的泰特州，所以我要
add a private integer which is the
添加一个私有整数
counter like so then when we get a
像这样的计数器然后当我们得到一个
message we're gonna increase that
消息，我们将增加
counter and I'm also gonna login info
柜台，我也要登录信息
message just to make this a bit more
消息只是为了使这一点更多
interactive and nice to look at
互动性好看
so you increased counter and then I'm
所以你增加柜台，然后我
going to print the value like this okay
像这样打印值
so now we have defined the protocol and
所以现在我们定义了协议
the state the logic of the actor what we
国家演员的逻辑我们
need now is to actually create the actor
现在需要的是实际创建演员
and to do that we need two things the
为此，我们需要做两件事
first thing is is something called props
第一件事就是所谓的道具
and props is like a descriptor for this
道具就像一个描述符
actor it will describe which class the
演员将描述哪个班级
actor is off and it will describe other
演员已关闭，它将描述其他
properties that I'm not going to kind of
我不会去的属性
touch in this webinar but it looks like
触摸此网络研讨会，但看起来
this we call props don't create and then
我们称之为道具不创造，然后
we give it the class so in our case
我们给它上课，所以在我们的情况下
counter dot class a very good habit is
反点课一个很好的习惯是
to create a factory for this because if
为此创建一个工厂，因为如果
we add constructor parameters to our
我们将构造函数参数添加到我们的
actor you see yourself that this is
演员，你看到自己，这是
using reflection or some tricks to
使用反射或一些技巧
instantiate and then we will have a
实例化，然后我们将有一个
runtime exception out of something that
运行时异常
could be a compile time exception right
可能是编译时异常的权利
so if I added a string constructor
所以如果我添加了一个字符串构造函数
parameter to counter
计数器参数
I could easily forget to add it's just
我很容易忘记添加它
props instance right where I actually
我实际在哪里的道具实例
describe how you create the actor so a
描述您如何创建演员，以便
good Factory
好工厂
a good habit is to define a props
一个好习惯是定义一个道具
Factory and this is something that I do
工厂，这是我要做的
so often so I have defined this live
很多次，所以我定义了这个直播
templates in IntelliJ 4 it's like so so
IntelliJ 4中的模板就像这样
in this way I will have a place closer
这样我将有一个更近的地方
to the actual constructor where I where
到实际的构造函数，我在哪里
I can remember to add eventual
我记得最后添加了
parameters but in our case we have no
参数，但在我们的情况下，我们没有
parameters okay so now we have a way to
参数好，所以现在我们有办法
create the props an actor doesn't kind
制作演员不喜欢的道具
of just we don't instantiate it
只是我们不实例化它
ourselves like a regular object so this
我们自己就像一个普通的物体，所以这
is a big difference from from a regular
与常规相比有很大的不同
object we use an actor system so the
对象，我们使用演员系统，所以
actor live sick cycle will be bound to
演员生病的周期必将
this actor system when we shot the actor
当我们拍摄演员时，这个演员系统
system down all the actors will stop for
系统崩溃，所有演员都会停下来
example so I'm going to start with
例子，所以我将开始
creating creating an instance of this
创建为此创建一个实例
actor system like so actor system dot
像这样的演员系统演员系统点
create I can give it a name next like so
创建我可以给它命名下一个像这样
and then using the system I will use
然后使用系统
actor of which takes the props and there
演员带道具，在那里
is two two variants of it one that takes
是它的两个两个变体
just two props and one that takes the
只有两个道具，一个需要
name I will get back to the name later
我稍后会回到名字
but it's almost always a good idea to
但这几乎总是一个好主意
give it the name so now I'm going to
给它起个名字，所以现在我要
call this counter dot props factory
将此柜台称为道具厂
method and then I'm going to give it a
方法，然后我要给它一个
name counter so when we create an actor
命名计数器，以便我们在创建演员时
with this actor off we get back this
离开这个演员，我们回来了
single way of interacting with an actor
与演员互动的单一方式
which is called an actress okay
叫做女演员好吗
if we look a bit that what we can do
如果我们看起来可以做些什么
with an actor if there is is really not
如果真的没有演员的话
so many methods and the most interesting
这么多的方法和最有趣的
one is this tell and tell will send a
一个是告诉，告诉将发送一个
message to this actor so we will create
给这位演员的信息，我们将创建
a new message here counter dot message
此处有新消息计数器点消息
create a new instance of it like so and
像这样创建一个新实例
then it takes the second parameter with
然后它用第二个参数
which is who sent the message but in
谁发送了消息但
this case where we don't really have a
在这种情况下，我们实际上并没有
sender we have a main thread and there
发送者，我们有一个主线程，那里
is no logic to kind of catch any replies
抓住任何答复是没有逻辑的
here so we will use actor if don't know
在这里，所以我们将使用演员，如果不知道
sender lights like so ok so let's just
发件人的灯像这样好，让我们来
try and round up to see it is super
尝试并四舍五入看看它是超级
basic example ok so we can see that we
基本示例好，所以我们可以看到我们
got a log entry with the increased
增加了一个日志条目
counter so this doesn't seem very
柜台，所以这似乎不是很
amazing or special because you could
惊人或特别，因为你可以
have just made a method that could
刚刚提出了一种方法，可以
increase a counter right so what is
增加柜台权，那是什么
interesting here is that this is totally
有趣的是，这完全是
safe from a concurrency concurrency
避免并发
point of view so we could actually do a
的观点，所以我们实际上可以做一个
loop like this we will create 5 threads
这样循环，我们将创建5个线程
like so or actually I could do it with a
这样或实际上我可以用一个
lambda and then oh that's actually let's
lambda然后哦，实际上是让我们
do it like this anyways and then in each
无论如何都要这样做，然后在每个
thread we will do another for loop so
线程，我们将做另一个for循环，所以
from each each thread we will send 5
从每个线程我们将发送5
messages and we will kick off all this
消息，我们将开始所有这一切
right away like so so this is where a
马上就这样，所以这是一个
regular method would
常规方法会
would not be safe since increasing the
将不安全，因为增加
counter isn't atomic so it actually
计数器不是原子的，所以实际上
consists of the operation of reading the
包括读取
value and then adding a number to the
值，然后将数字添加到
value and then writing the value and
值，然后写入值和
there's also visibility things with with
还有与之相关的可见性
the Java memory remodel that would make
Java内存重构将使
it so that we could lose increments if
它可以使我们失去增量
we would do this with a regular method
我们将使用常规方法执行此操作
and immutable variable so now if I run
和不可变的变量，所以现在如果我运行
this you should see that we get the
这你应该看到我们得到了
counter increased to 25 in the end okay
计数器最终增加到25
so this was a very basic sample of
所以这是一个非常基本的例子
having mutable state inside of an actor
在演员内部具有可变状态
let's move on to another sample so I
让我们继续另一个示例，我
also said that a way that the nectar can
也说花蜜可以
react them on messages is that it
对消息做出反应是
changes its behavior so let's make a
改变它的行为，让我们做一个
sample that that's exactly that and I
样本就是那个，我
have this idea which is a alarm so we're
有这个想法，这是一个警报，所以我们
going to create a new actor which is
要创建一个新的演员
called alarm which extends the abstract
称为警报，它扩展了抽象
logging actor to get some logging then
记录演员，然后获取一些记录
we will define few protocol messages
我们将定义一些协议消息
the first being activity so there was
首先是活动，所以有
something happening there was a sensor
发生了什么事，有一个传感器
telling us that something happened in
告诉我们发生了什么事
the in the house where this alarm is
该警报所在的房子里
installed and then we have the
安装，然后我们有
possibility to disable the alarm right
禁用警报权限的可能性
to disable the alarm you will need a
要禁用警报，您将需要一个
password because if we didn't have a
密码，因为如果我们没有
password then the thief would be able to
密码，然后小偷将能够
just turn off the alarm and when it goes
只需关闭闹钟，当它响起时
off
关
and we also want to have a message that
而且我们还希望有一条消息
is for enabling the alarm and that will
用于启用警报，这将
also take the password right because we
也请正确输入密码，因为我们
don't want one of the kids to
不想让一个孩子
accidentally set off turn on the alarm
不小心关掉警报器
like so and now we will have we will
这样，现在我们将拥有
need to have a preset password for the
需要为
alarm so I'm gonna add some kind of
报警，所以我要添加某种
constant here and then we will take it
恒定在这里，然后我们将它
to the customer like so and then I can
这样给客户，然后我可以
right away create the props factory that
立即创建道具工厂
I told you about before and it will also
我之前告诉过你，它也会
take down the password
取下密码
pass it along to the actual constructor
将其传递给实际的构造函数
then we will have two behaviors so the
那么我们将有两种行为，所以
first one you're not sure about the pipe
第一个你不确定管道
yet the first one will be when the alarm
但是第一个是当警报
is enabled and the other one is when the
已启用，另一个是当
alarm is disabled right the actual pipe
实际的管道已禁用警报
is just like I showed you before and we
就像我以前给你看的一样
were setting up the initial behavior of
建立了最初的行为
the first sample just a partial function
第一个样本只是部分函数
which goes from object to box unit which
从对象到盒子单位
is a bit weird
有点奇怪
but this is how it looks like so
但这就是它的样子
and I make them final because we're
我把它们定下来，因为我们
going to define them and they're never
要定义它们，它们永远不会
going to shake and she's just going to
会发抖，她只会
switch between these two editors right
在这两个编辑器之间切换
and then I can say in the end of the of
然后我可以说
the alarm constructor that we will start
我们将开始的警报构造函数
with disabled right we don't want the
与残疾人权利，我们不想
alarm to be on and we install the alarm
警报打开，我们安装警报
okay so let's define this now then so
好吧，现在让我们定义一下
enabled is constructed using the receive
使用接收构造接收
builder and we will match activity and
生成器，我们将匹配活动和
then we will call a method on activity
那么我们将在活动上调用一个方法
like so and then it will get the
像这样，然后它将得到
activity as a message and I made the
活动作为消息，我做了
message empty it doesn't contain any any
消息为空，不包含任何消息
states so we're actually ignore ignoring
状态，因此我们实际上忽略了忽略
it so I can just call it ignore it here
所以我可以称之为忽略它
let's see if I spell something weirdly
让我们看看我是否奇怪地拼写了一些东西
yeah I'm sorry I can't spell activity
是的，我很抱歉我无法拼写活动
like so so when we get the neck tivity
像这样，当我们得到脖子的定性
then we will sound the alarm so I'm
然后我们会发出警报，所以我
gonna use warning for this and it's
要为此使用警告，它是
gonna be really alarm alarm like so and
像这样真的会成为警报
then we have another thing that can
那么我们还有另一件事可以
happen when we when the alarm is enabled
当我们启用警报时发生
and that is that we get the message to
那就是我们得到的信息
disable it so I'm just gonna create
禁用它，所以我要创建
another method on disable like this
这样的另一个禁用方法
and this time we actually will will have
这次我们实际上将拥有
some we will have some data inside of
一些我们里面会有一些数据
the disable message because we have that
禁用消息，因为我们有
password right so we will want to check
密码正确，所以我们将要检查
if the password we have is equal with
如果我们拥有的密码等于
the password in the message like so and
消息中的密码是这样的，
if it is then we will get context and
如果是这样，我们将获得上下文和
become so we will become disabled like
变得如此，我们将变得像
so right if not also that's absolutely
好吧，如果不是，那绝对是
loving to make it clear nice alarm
希望清楚清楚
disabled like so and if not we will have
像这样的残疾人，如果没有，我们将有
this log warning someone who didn't know
此日志警告不认识的人
the password try to disable it like so
密码尝试像这样禁用它
and then in the end here we're going to
然后最后我们要
do they call tilt to actually construct
他们叫倾斜来实际构造
this receive receive block and then
这个接收接收块，然后
we're gonna do this say bold which will
我们要说的是大胆的
be receive builder dot match match is
被接收生成器点匹配，匹配为
going to take only enable dot class
将只启用点类
enable like so because if there is
这样启用，因为如果有
activity when the alarm is turned off
闹钟关闭时的活动
then we don't care there's not nothing
那我们就不在乎
gonna happen nothing's gonna happen when
什么时候都不会发生
when the alarm is disabled except for
禁用警报时
when we try to enable it
当我们尝试启用它
and again we're going to check if the
再次，我们将检查
password is correct and then we're gonna
密码是正确的，然后我们将
enable the same way we do I get contacts
启用与我联系的方式相同
that become enabled and if the password
启用，如果密码
was wrong then it's probably not that
是错的，那可能不是
serious as the someone trying to disable
像试图禁用的人一样认真
the alarm with the wrong password so
密码错误的警报
we're just gonna do an info someone
我们只是要向某人提供信息
failed to enable the enabled B alarm
无法启用已启用的B警报
like so okay and then in the end here
像这样好，然后最后在这里
we're going to call build to complete
我们将调用构建完成
receive so now we have created an actor
收到所以现在我们已经创建了一个演员
that has two different behaviors and it
有两种不同的行为
will switch between those behaviors as a
将在这些行为之间切换
reaction to a message so let's play
对消息的反应，让我们玩
around a bit with it use the system to
大约与它使用系统
create an instance of the actor actor
创建actor actor的实例
off with the props and we have a
用道具，我们有一个
password and we give it a name as well
密码，我们也给它起一个名字
alarm like so and then we catch the
像这样报警，然后我们抓住
actor if that we get back which is
演员，如果我们回来，那是
actually the alarm so let's call it the
实际上是警报，所以我们称之为
alarm okay and then let's send it a few
报警好，然后我们发送一些
of these messages so we will start with
这些消息中，所以我们将从
activity to kind of show that it starts
活动表明开始
out in this disabled mode and then we're
退出此禁用模式，然后我们
going to enable it but we're going to
要启用它，但我们要
use the wrong password and then we will
使用错误的密码，然后我们将
enable it with the right password then
然后使用正确的密码启用它
we will do some activity when the alarm
报警时我们会做一些活动
is enabled then we will try to disable
已启用，那么我们将尝试禁用
the alarm
闹钟
with the wrong password and finally we
使用错误的密码，最后我们
will disable the alarm with the right
将禁用带有右侧的警报
password and then trigger some activity
密码，然后触发一些活动
okay so let's just run this and see what
好吧，让我们运行它，看看
happens so we can see that someone
发生，所以我们可以看到有人
failed to enable the alarm that is the
无法启用警报
first log message we get and actually
我们收到的第一个日志消息实际上
there was an activity before that but
在那之前有活动，但是
since the alarm was disabled we didn't
由于警报已禁用，我们没有
vlog anything we then an enable the
vlog任何东西，然后我们启用
alarm and then there was activity so it
报警，然后有活动，所以它
triggered the alarm then someone tried
触发警报，然后有人尝试
to disable the passed the alarm with the
使用禁用通过的警报
wrong password and Anila we disabled it
错误的密码，我们禁用了Anila
and then we can see that the activity
然后我们可以看到活动
sent in the end didn't trigger the alarm
最后发送没有触发警报
okay so again this is just this is
好的，再说一次，这就是
something in this context where I do it
在这种情况下我要做的事情
from one thread it's not very impressive
从一个线程来看不是很令人印象深刻
maybe but the fact that we could send
也许但事实是我们可以发送
these messages from any thread in the
这些消息来自
entire JVM and it would be totally safe
整个JVM，这将是完全安全的
it's kind of impressive just I think
我觉得这令人印象深刻
that okay so let's go back to a bit of
好的，让我们回到一点
slides so I mentioned that we created
幻灯片，所以我提到我们创建了
the actor with a name but I didn't
有名字的演员，但我没有
mention kind of what in what context
提到什么在什么情况下
that is useful or what this name is what
那很有用或者这个名字叫什么
it means so the actors are arranged in a
这意味着演员被安排在一个
hierarchy when we create an actor
创建演员时的等级
directly from the system it will live
直接从系统将生存
under the user Guardian which is an
在用户Guardian下
actor that always exists it's created by
永远存在的演员是由
the system when it starts up we give a
系统启动时，我们给
second parameter to this actor of method
方法参与者的第二个参数
it will use that parameter as a name in
它将使用该参数作为名称
this actor hierarchy inside of an actor
演员内部的这个演员层次
we can call get context an actor off in
我们可以称呼获取上下文为演员
this case we're creating an actor that
在这种情况下，我们正在创建一个演员
will be a child of our actor so it will
将是我们演员的孩子，所以
have its life
有生命
cycle sort of bound to this today sector
周期的种类绑定到今天的部门
means that if we stop my actor in this
就是说如果我们停止我的演员
case it will also stop my child so my
那样也会阻止我的孩子，所以我的
child can never survive longer than the
孩子的生存期永远不会超过
the parent in this hierarchy it also
在此层次结构中的父级
means something very special with
意味着很特别的东西
regards to failure handling so I will
关于失败处理，所以我会
start first with an important
首先从重要开始
distinction and this distinction is
区别，这个区别是
Error validation errors versus failures
错误验证错误与失败
so in a system there is validation
所以在系统中有验证
errors which is kind of validating some
错误，可以验证一些错误
input from an untrusted source this is
来自不受信任来源的输入，这是
something that will belong in the in the
将会属于
error handling or in the logic of a
错误处理或逻辑
method in this actor so if it is an
这个actor中的方法，如果它是一个
exception then it will be a try catch
例外，那将是一个尝试
catching that illegal number format for
捕获该非法数字格式
example a failure on the other hand that
另一方面，失败的例子
is something that the actor cannot
是演员无法做到的
actually deal with himself so for
实际上对付自己
example that could be with a database it
可能与数据库有关的示例
could be a connection timed out
可能是连接超时
exception so the common thing in in
例外，所以在
regular Java code would be to throw this
常规的Java代码将抛出该错误
exception outwards and you would have
异常向外，你将有
some business logic layer and that has
一些业务逻辑层
no idea what to do with the connection
不知道该怎么办
timed out exception so it will throw it
超时异常，因此将其抛出
outwards and then you will have a
向外，然后你将有一个
presentation layer which totally have no
表示层，完全没有
idea what to do with a connection error
知道如何处理连接错误
connection failure so it will log it and
连接失败，因此它将记录它并
show a failure page user so with ACTA we
显示失败页面的用户，因此使用ACTA我们
have this idea that we should instead
有这个想法，我们应该改为
try to send the failure somewhere where
尝试将故障发送到某处
it's useful somewhere where we can
在可以的地方很有用
actually act upon it so this is called
实际上对它采取行动，所以这叫做
supervision when a message comes to an
消息到达时的监督
actor and triggers an exception if that
演员，并触发异常
exception is not caught in the logic of
异常未陷入逻辑
the actor it will go to the parent of
演员会去的父母
the actor and
演员和
parent of the actor will have the chance
演员的父母将有机会
to decide what should happen because of
决定由于
this failure and the things it can
这种失败及其可能发生的事情
decide between is to say that the child
决定之间是说孩子
should resume and this means that it
应该恢复，这意味着它
should keep processing messages but just
应该继续处理消息，但是
ignore this one because this current
忽略这一点，因为当前
message was caused some something faulty
消息是由某些错误引起的
another option is that it can restart
另一个选择是它可以重新启动
the child so this is useful if the child
孩子，所以这对孩子很有用
has a state and it's possible that the
具有状态，并且可能
state gone went invalid because of the
状态因
because of the failure so this will
因为失败所以这会
cause the child actor to be stopped and
使儿童演员停止演出并
a new instance will be started and any
一个新实例将启动，并且任何
actor if that someone had to this actor
演员，如果有人要这个演员
from the from the outside will then lead
从外面将导致
to this new started actor any messages
给这个新开始的演员的任何消息
that was in the mailbox except for the
在邮箱中，除了
one that caused a failure will be
导致失败的将是
processed by this new actor so this is a
由这个新演员处理，所以这是一个
really neat thing for example the
真的很整洁的东西，例如
database connection broke we can start a
数据库连接断开，我们可以启动一个
new actor which will start up a new
新演员，这将启动一个新的
connection if possible and will make the
如果可能的话，将使
system sort of self heal in some
系统在某种程度上自我修复
circumstances there is no real there is
情况没有真实存在
no way to deal with the failure and the
没有办法处理失败和
only option is to stop so this is
唯一的选择就是停止，所以这是
another yet another option for the
另一种选择
parents to deal with the exception this
父母处理这个例外
is for example what happens if there is
例如，如果有
of an exception thrown from the
从中抛出的异常
constructor by default so if it's
默认情况下的构造函数，如果
impossible to create an instance of the
无法创建该实例
actor because of an error then it won't
演员因为错误而不会
very it isn't very likely that you can
非常不可能
create a new instance of it and that
创建一个新的实例
will work ok there is one option I
会好的，我有一个选择
haven't shown on this slide which is
没有在这张幻灯片上显示
escalate which means I don't know what
升级意味着我不知道
to do with this I will pass it on to my
为此，我会将其传递给我
parent and my parent will decide what to
父母和我父母将决定如何
do but notice that in this case then
但是要注意，在这种情况下
that will affect the entire
那会影响到整个
in the attire here a key so or a larger
在这里的服装关键是一个或多个
part of the hierarchy so in this case
层次结构的一部分，所以在这种情况下
when the volcano erupts in the in the
当火山爆发在
child if I would pass that exception
孩子，如果我愿意通过那个例外
upwards with escalate it would mean that
随着升级而上升，这意味着
the decision that the user guardian node
用户监护节点的决定
takes four for supervision will affect
需要四个人进行监督会影响
the entire subtree of actors in the
演员的整个子树
hierarchy okay so because of this it's
层次结构好吧，因此，
important to kind of create deep ear
对于建立深深的耳朵来说很重要
keys rather than white hierarchies we
关键，而不是我们的白色层次结构
want
想
sections of our system that can be
我们系统中可以
restarted and then will work if
重新启动，然后将工作，如果
something goes wrong rather than
出问题了而不是
something that full versus the entire
完整的东西与整体的东西
system to go down okay so let's see if
系统出现故障，好让我们看看
there was something I missed here yeah
我在这里错过了一些东西
if we stop the reactor where does the
如果我们停止反应堆，
active point where does message is sent
发送消息的活动点
to the actor go there is this special
去演员那里有这个特别
destination innaka which is called the
目的地innaka，称为
dead letter office which is actually
死信办公室，实际上是
something that real post offices have
真正的邮局有的东西
it's a place where letters do you don't
这是一个你不写字母的地方
know about the recipient or the
了解收件人或
recipient doesn't exist anymore we'll go
收件人不存在了，我们去
so with ARCA this means that they will
因此，使用ARCA，这意味着他们将
be logged in the system log with some
被记录在系统日志中
information about where they were headed
有关他们去向的信息
but it's it's kind of useful to see when
但这是很有用的
when something is wrong that that you
当有什么不对劲的时候
can see what which actor isn't there
可以看到哪个演员不在
anymore
不再
okay so let's play around a bit with how
好吧，让我们来玩一下
to actually do this in code so in sample
在代码中实际执行此操作，因此在示例中
3 here I have prepared a little bit by
3我在这里准备了一点
creating a child that can't be trusted
创造一个不能被信任的孩子
so in this sample it will accept
因此在此示例中它将接受
messages of the type command and when it
类型命令的消息及其何时
gets the command it will increase the
得到命令，它将增加
counter and if that
柜台，如果那
message is evenly divided scible by four
消息被四等分
it will throw an exception a runtime
它将在运行时引发异常
exception if it is not device level by
如果不是设备级别，则为异常
four we will just look that we got a
四，我们只会看到我们有一个
comment and then we have the props
评论，然后我们有道具
factory just like I told you about
就像我告诉你的一样
before and then we're gonna create this
之前然后我们要创建这个
actor not from the main method of this
演员不是从这个主要方法
application but instead we're going to
应用程序，但相反，我们要
do it from another actor so I'm actually
从另一个演员那里做，所以我实际上
going to change this into abstract
要将其变为抽象
logging actor like before to get some
像以前的伐木演员一样得到一些
nice nice options for for logging and
用于记录和
and then when it starts we're gonna do
然后当它开始时，我们要做
get context actor off now trustworthy
让上下文演员脱颖而出
child of tropes like so let's give it a
这样的比喻之子，让我们给它一个
nine name child awesome okay and then
九个名字的孩子很棒，然后
we're going to keep a reference to it
我们将继续引用它
like so and then for any incoming
像这样，然后对于任何传入
message we get to this supervisor we're
我们得到这个主管的信息
just gonna pass it on to the child so
只是要把它传递给孩子，所以
that means that we call receive and then
这意味着我们叫接收然后
we use the receive builder and we match
我们使用接收构建器，我们匹配
on any message and we just pass those on
在任何消息上，我们只是将其传递给
to child and we can do do this with a
给孩子，我们可以做到这一点
special special method so before we have
特殊的特殊方法
used tell to send messages to actors and
用于告诉发送消息给演员和
I will take an assembler so that the
我将带一个汇编器，以便
actor can reply but in this in this
演员可以回复，但是在此
context we would like if the child would
如果孩子愿意，我们希望
choose to reply to the sender we would
选择回覆寄件者，我们会
like that to be the original sender
像这样成为原始发件人
rather than the parents so then we can
而不是父母，那么我们可以
use this forward method instead so we
请改用此前进方法
just forward this message to the child
只是把这个信息转发给孩子
and then we pass this gift context
然后我们传递这个礼物上下文
the context of the actor and then we
演员的背景，然后我们
built so like that so now we have now we
这样建造，所以现在我们有了
have created this hero T just like I
像我一样创造了这个英雄T
told you about we will have this we have
告诉你我们将拥有这个
the user guardian like this user and
像该用户这样的用户监护人和
then we will have this actor which we
然后我们会有这个演员
haven't really created yet but we'll
尚未真正创建，但我们会
create it from the main method and we
从主要方法创建它，我们
have created a child so this child will
已经创造了一个孩子，所以这个孩子会
have this complete path to you in this
在这方面有完整的路径
actor here okay okay and then the other
演员在这里好吧好吧，然后其他
thing we need to do is to define this
我们需要做的就是定义这个
supervision strategy which is what
监管策略是什么
happens when the child throws an
当孩子扔一个
exception so to do this we will override
例外，为此，我们将覆盖
a method called supervision strategy and
一种称为监督策略的方法
it's supposed to return a supervision
它应该返回监督
strategy and there is two basic kinds of
策略，有两种基本的
them there is one for I'm sorry all for
他们有一个，我很抱歉
one which will take the decision that we
一个将决定我们
we make out of the out of the exception
我们做出了例外
and we will apply that to our all our
我们会将其应用于我们所有
children this is like the in most cases
孩子，这在大多数情况下就像
this is not what we want we want to deal
这不是我们想要处理的
with each children each child on their
每个孩子都有一个孩子
own sort of but we might have some kind
自己的，但我们可能有某种
of shared shared context of some kind
某种共享共享上下文
some ideas that it isn't useful to keep
一些想法是没有用的
the children alive if we have to stop
如果我们必须停下来，孩子们还活着
one of them for example but in this case
例如其中之一，但在这种情况下
we're going to use the one for one
我们将一一使用
strategy and it will take a few
策略，这将需要一些
parameters the first one is how many
参数第一个是多少
retries will be done so if the actor
重试将这样做，如果演员
will if we say restart button once again
如果我们再说一次重启按钮，
this many times so let's say 10 times
这么多，所以说十倍
within a specific duration
在特定时间内
then we will give up because it
那么我们会放弃，因为
obviously isn't any used to to try to
显然没有人习惯尝试
get this running
运行这个
notice here that little special thing
注意这里的小事
that is easy to get wrong is that the
容易出错的是
duration is from skl about concurrent
持续时间来自skål关于并发
duration and it's not from the new job
持续时间，而不是新工作
at a time ApS okay so we're going to say
一次ApS好，所以我们要说
it ten times in ten seconds so so if it
它在十秒钟内十次，所以如果它
fails more than ten times in ten seconds
在十秒钟内失败十次以上
then it will give up and just stop the
然后它将放弃，只是停止
child and then we have the final thing
孩子，然后我们有最后一件事
which is again the partial function and
这又是部分函数，
again we have a special builder for this
同样，我们为此有一个特殊的建造者
innaka so we have there now I had a
innaka，所以我们现在在那里
brain brain freeze your brain block we
大脑大脑冻结了我们的大脑
have the strategy builder we have the
有战略建设者，我们有
supervision strategy builder now we have
监管策略构建者现在我们有了
the decider builder sorry and decide the
决策者对不起，决定
builder works exactly like receive
生成器的工作方式与接收完全相同
builder and it will match on a class
生成器，它将与一个类匹配
which is an exception so in this case I
这是一个例外，所以在这种情况下，我
showed you the norm don't trust for this
告诉你规范对此不信任
child which would throw a runtime
会抛出运行时的孩子
exception so we will match on this
例外，因此我们将对此进行匹配
runtime exception here and then when we
运行时异常在这里，然后当我们
get this exception we have the chance to
得到这个例外，我们有机会
kind of look closer at it maybe look at
看起来更近一点，也许看一下
the message or some specific flags
消息或某些特定标志
inside of the exception but in this case
在例外之内，但在这种情况下
we're just going to return a something
我们只是要返回一些东西
called the directive to say that we want
调用指令说我们想要
to restart or that we want to start very
重新启动，或者我们想开始
soon and to get access to those I'm just
很快就可以访问那些我只是
gonna use a shortcut here strategies so
要在这里使用捷径策略
I'm gonna do a static import of
我要静态导入
strategies that lives inside of this
存在于其中的策略
supervisor strategy class and now we
主管战略课，现在我们
will have access to pursue
将有机会追求
I start stop and Escalade just like I
我像我一样开始停车和凯雷德
described so let's start with restart
描述，所以让我们开始重新启动
here and see how this works out and then
在这里，看看如何解决，然后
in the end need to actually build the
最后需要实际构建
yeah decider like so in this case also
是的，在这种情况下，决策者也是如此
we are actually not actually not
我们实际上不是
changing anything or depending on
改变任何东西或取决于
anything in the inside of the actor sure
演员里面的任何东西肯定
we could have defined this strategy as a
我们本可以将此策略定义为
static field to avoid creating a new one
静态字段以避免创建新字段
every time so I'm just gonna I'm just
每次，我都会
gonna do that and extract constant like
要做那并提取常数
so so now every instance we would create
所以现在我们要创建的每个实例
that the supervisor will have the same
主管将具有相同的
strategy but everything is immutable
战略，但一切都是一成不变的
here so that's not a problem okay so
在这里，这没问题，所以
final piece of the puzzle is to actually
最后的难题是
create an instance of the supervisor and
创建主管的实例，并
run it so we do a system actor of
运行它，所以我们做一个系统参与者
supervisor and I didn't create the props
主管，我没有创造道具
factory sorry
工厂对不起
so I'll just sneak that in here like so
所以我就这样偷偷溜进去
supervisor dot props so and then I will
主管点道具等等然后我会
capture that in a variable called
捕获到一个称为
provider and then we will create a for
提供者，然后我们将为
loop sending it bunch of messages like
循环发送一堆消息，例如
so supervisor not tell to send it the
所以主管不告诉发送
message and now the actual protocol was
消息，现在实际的协议是
defined in the in the not trustworthy
在不信任中定义
child so it will be a new non
孩子，所以它将是一个新的非
trustworthy child not command like so
可信赖的孩子不是这样的命令
and again we have no sender here in the
再次，我们在这里没有发件人
main thread so we just pass this act the
主线程，所以我们只是通过这个行为
rest of no son
没有儿子的其余部分
okay so let's run this and see what
好吧，让我们运行它，看看
happens
发生
so we can see that the child's dog
这样我们可以看到孩子的狗
studied got a command got a command got
学习了一个命令得到了一个命令
a command and then we reached a number
命令，然后我们到达一个号码
that is evenly divided by four so I will
被四等分，所以我会
throw an exception and this error is
引发异常，此错误是
actually logged by the final supervisor
由最终主管实际记录
so if we look in the in the actual in
因此，如果我们查看实际的
the non trustworthy child it doesn't log
不值得信任的孩子，它不会登录
anything it's just throwing an exception
任何只是抛出异常的东西
and what happens then we all of a sudden
然后发生了什么，我们突然之间
have a new instance running here
有一个新的实例在这里运行
non-trust or a child which will log
不信任或将登录的孩子
three commands and then it's evenly
三个命令，然后均匀地
device' built by three so how can we
设备”由三个人构建，那么我们如何
make this a bit more clear I will add
让这一点更加清楚，我将添加
this counter here so we can actually see
这个柜台在这里，所以我们实际上可以看到
that it will reset okay so let's run it
它将重置好，让我们运行它
again and you can see that we've got
再次，您可以看到我们已经
command one come on to comment three and
命令一来评论三，
then it got the fourth one and then
然后它得到了第四，然后
after it should restart we have a new a
它应该重新启动后，我们有一个新的
new non-trust for each child so it will
为每个孩子建立新的不信任关系
start at one again so the state has been
重新开始，所以状态一直
reset let's see what happens if we
重置让我们看看如果我们
instead use resume okay so we can see
改用简历好吧，所以我们可以看到
that we get the message of the exception
我们得到异常消息
is log as a worn instead of an error
被记录为磨损而不是错误
which restored the exception was but
恢复异常是
then it will continue and it has its
然后它将继续，并且它具有
state kept so we will continue from five
状态保持不变，所以我们将从五个继续
and and six and seven and then it's
还有六个和七个然后是
evenly divided scible by four again and
再次将圣经平均除以四，
then we will continue upwards with the
然后我们将继续向上
state
州
let's try also then the stop strategy so
让我们也尝试停止策略
this will make the first exception that
这将成为第一个例外
happens the actor will be stopped and
发生，演员将被停止，
again we get an error log because this
再次，我们得到一个错误日志，因为
is something fairly
相当公平
serious and then we can see that the
认真的，然后我们可以看到
following messages they will go to what
以下消息，他们将去什么
I talked about before did that letter q
我之前说过那封信q
so we can see that it was intended to go
所以我们可以看到它原本打算去
to users supervisor child but there was
给用户主管孩子，但是有
no such child and is that it went to the
没有这样的孩子，是它去了
dead letter Q okay if we do escalate
死信Q好的，如果我们升级
which is the fourth one then just to be
这是第四个
complete we can see how it's even the
完成，我们可以看到它甚至是
message that was intended sorry what I
本来打算对不起我的消息
didn't mention is that there is a
没说是有一个
default strategy installed so if we
默认策略已安装，因此如果我们
don't define it then essentially any
不要定义它，基本上
exception in the constructor will stop
构造函数中的异常将停止
the actor the child and any other
演员，孩子和其他任何演员
exception that happens when the actor is
当演员是
processing a message will need to
处理一条消息将需要
restart so in this case we will get the
重新启动，所以在这种情况下，我们将获得
supervisor restarted so let's go back to
主管重新启动，让我们回到
slides how is this actually happening
幻灯片这实际上是怎么发生的
them well every actor has got a mailbox
他们很好，每个演员都有一个邮箱
which is kind of a queue so when you
这有点排队，所以当你
send it a message that will be include
向其发送将包含的消息
on to that queue and that will lead to
进入那个队列，这将导致
the actor being scheduled on something
演员被安排在某事上
called a dispatcher and its dispatcher
称为调度员及其调度员
is essentially a thread pool or an
本质上是一个线程池或
executor service from the Java
Java的执行程序服务
concurrent vibrissae libraries the
并发触须库
actual actors are sort of decoupled from
实际的演员与
threads so when an actor is not
线程，因此当演员不在
processing a message it will not occupy
处理一条不会占用的消息
a thread when an actor gets a message we
当演员收到消息时的线程
will link you itself on the dispatcher
将您自身链接到调度程序上
and at some point the executors will
在某个时候，执行者会
have a thread free and that will
有一个免费的线程，那将
let the actor execute process that
让演员执行的过程
message this means that the actor isn't
消息，这意味着演员不是
tied to a specific thread but it can run
绑定到特定线程，但可以运行
on any of the threads on the batcher
在批处理程序上的任何线程上
the default dispatcher uses for queuing
默认调度程序用于排队
pool which means that for which is
池，这意味着
optimized for for messages or for
为消息或消息优化
processing that isn't blocking so that
没有阻塞的处理
is something really important to
真的很重要
understand about akka that it's if you
了解阿卡，如果你
want to do blocking then the default
要阻止然后默认
thread pool is built for short CPU bound
建立线程池是为了缩短CPU绑定时间
jobs if you put stuff that will actually
工作，如果你放一些东西，实际上
wait for a network call or file system
等待网络通话或文件系统
right then then that thread will be
然后那个线程将是
occupied with this even though it's not
即使不是
actually doing anything right so there's
实际上做正确的事，所以
orders of magnitude in difference
差异的数量级
between processing something in memory
在处理内存中的内容之间
and waiting for something that comes
等待着即将来临的事情
over the network and if we have a few
通过网络，如果我们有几个
threads and we expect these jobs to be
线程，我们希望这些工作能够
very short and we let these the actors
很短，我们让这些演员
then do something very very long and
然后做很长的事情，
blocking then that will lead to other
阻止然后将导致其他
actors not being left to run or process
演员不被允许运行或处理
their messages so a very important thing
他们的信息非常重要
if you use akka is to understand what is
如果您使用Akka是为了了解什么
blocking and what is not and isolate
阻止和不隔离
blocking on to its own dispatcher so
阻止自己的调度程序
this is going to be my final sample I
这将是我的最终样品
say that I'm already a bit over time but
说我已经有点时间了，但是
I will quickly show it so this time I'm
我会很快显示出来，所以这次我
not going to code but I'm going to show
不打算编码，但我要展示
you so this kind of ties together a few
你这样的联系在一起
different things I have been talking
我一直在谈论不同的事情
about but I'm gonna just focus in on
关于，但我只专注于
this blocking part so I have created a
这个阻塞的部分，所以我创建了一个
class that kind of simulates me
类模拟我
a synchronous database connection so
同步数据库连接
like JDBC you issue a query and it will
像JDBC一样，您发出查询，它将
block the thread until the database
阻塞线程直到数据库
server has replied so it doesn't
服务器已回复，因此没有
actually process it's just it's just
实际处理它只是
blocked by waiting for for data coming
通过等待数据来阻止
back over the socket so this is
回到插座，所以这是
simulated by a thread not sleep here so
由线程模拟在这里不睡觉
thread not sleep is very it looks very
线程不睡觉是非常它看起来非常
much like a a blocking operation because
很像一个阻塞操作，因为
it will actually not really do anything
它实际上不会做任何事情
with the thread but it will occupy the
与线程，但它将占用
threads until if this time is passed so
线程，直到这段时间过去为止
what we do to kind of isolate this is
我们要做的隔离类型是
that we in akka in our application
在我们的应用程序中
configuration of this application so I
这个应用程序的配置，所以我
haven't covered this before but there is
以前没有介绍过，但是有
a built-in library in actor that will
actor中的内置库
pick up configuration for your
为您挑选配置
application in a specific format that
特定格式的应用程序
looks a bit like JSON it's called a Cho
看起来有点像JSON，称为Cho
see um I think so in this configuration
看到我认为在这种配置
file we have defined a blocking
文件我们定义了一个阻止
dispatcher so a separate thread pool
调度程序，所以有一个单独的线程池
essentially which we configure to have a
本质上，我们将其配置为具有
specific number of threads and which we
具体的线程数，我们
then when we have a blocking actor
然后当我们有一个阻碍演员
isolate that actor onto by creating the
通过创建
props but then saying with dispatcher
道具，然后跟调度员说
this is the name of the dispatcher that
这是调度员的名字
we defined in the configuration file so
我们在配置文件中定义了
this way there will be a separate thread
这样会有一个单独的线程
pool for those blocking actors and the
为那些阻碍演员和
other actors can churn along processing
其他演员可以在处理过程中搅动
messages without problems even though
即使没有问题的消息
the database thread pool is blocked even
数据库线程池甚至被阻止
though all those threads are being
尽管所有这些线程
blocked there the other actors can do
封锁其他演员可以做的
stuff which they want okay I'm not going
他们想要的东西，我不去
to look more I think get this last
看更多，我想最后
sample so I guess you can maybe take a
样品，所以我想你可以拿一个
look at it on your own there will be a
自己看，会有一个
link in the end so
链接到底是这样
some repetition of some do's and don'ts
一些重复的做与不做
that I may be mentioned and some stuff I
可能会提到我和一些东西
haven't mentioned don't put everything
没提到就不要放所有东西
in a flat tire key but make this kind of
用flat胎的钥匙，但使这种
deeper here keys and push dangerous work
在这里更深的钥匙，推动危险的工作
downwards because that is how you can
向下，因为那是你可以的
make smaller parts fail independently
使较小的零件独立失效
and have them recover from failure make
让他们从失败中恢复过来
sure that you isolate blocking so that
确保隔离阻塞，以便
you don't affect actors that that don't
你不会影响那些不会的演员
do blocking at all with their with the
确实与他们的封锁
blocking actors so a good example would
阻止演员，这样一个很好的例子
be you're writing a web application and
是您正在编写Web应用程序，并且
you have some actors that will call it
你有一些演员会称之为
relational database and then you have
关系数据库，然后
some actors that actually have all their
实际上拥有所有演员的一些演员
data in memory already and they can just
数据已经在内存中，他们可以
reply to the requests very quickly so if
很快回复请求，所以如果
you would run all of these sectors on
您将在所有这些部门
the same thread pool then the blocking
相同的线程池然后阻塞
ones would stop the first one from
会阻止第一个
executing as well but if you isolate
同样执行，但如果您隔离
them then the first one will be able to
他们然后第一个将能够
serve requests even though the slow ones
服务请求，即使速度较慢
are overwhelmed with slow requests don't
被缓慢的请求所淹没
write all your logic inside your actors
将所有逻辑记录在演员中
and don't build don't write all your
并且不要建立不要写所有的
logic inside the the lambdas that you
Lambda内部的逻辑
can give to this receive builder and
可以给这个接收建造者和
decider builder but instead push it
决策者，但推它
outwards sort of best case make it
向外的最好的情况使它
regular logic like you would always
像往常一样的常规逻辑
write in Java and then use that inside
用Java编写然后在内部使用
of actors to kind of organize them with
演员来组织他们
synchronous boundaries and allow them to
同步边界，并允许他们
run concurrently make sure that all
同时运行，确保所有
messages are immutable or you will have
消息是不可变的，否则您将拥有
problems with different actors not
不同演员的问题不是
seeing stuff that you changed in the
看到您在
message because of how their Java memory
消息，因为它们的Java内存如何
model that works and that the actors can
有效的模型，演员可以
run on any of these threads that you
在您运行的任何这些线程上运行
have on the dispatcher in the executor
在执行者的调度员上
service of dispatcher although
虽然调度员的服务
everything with with actors because it
与演员在一起的一切，因为它
doesn't really make sense all the time
一直都没有意义
to recruit asynchronous boundaries
招募异步边界
between things
事物之间
just do it where it's actually useful
只是在实际有用的地方做
and this is something you can probably
这是你可能可以做到的
now drawn on a whiteboard and think
现在画在白板上，想一想
about what things can happen in parallel
关于什么事情可以并行发生
and what what things cannot happen in
以及什么事情不可能发生
parallel so for example as a Enterprise
并行，例如作为企业
Java developer your first kind of
Java开发人员的第一种
architectural tool would maybe be the
建筑工具可能是
three-tier architecture where you have
您拥有的三层架构
the presentation and then the business
演示文稿，然后是业务
logic and then the database and it's
逻辑，然后是数据库，
maybe not so useful to use these tears
也许用这些眼泪没那么有用
as abstractions or places where you
作为抽象或您所在的地方
would put the asynchronous boundaries
将异步边界
maybe around the database because you
也许围绕数据库，因为您
will have 10 database connections that
将有10个数据库连接
you need to share between different
你需要在不同之间分享
parts of the system but maybe the actual
系统的某些部分，但可能是实际的
logic for rendering the response parsing
呈现响应解析的逻辑
the request and processing business
请求和处理业务
logic belong in the same kind of
逻辑属于同一种
asynchronous island the same actor who
异步岛同一演员谁
knows ok so in addition to what I have
知道，所以除了我拥有的
told you about there's two big things in
告诉你里面有两件事
a kadai I think needs the service
我认为需要服务的kadai
mentioned and the first thing is like a
提到，第一件事就像
cluster and given that actors are ill
群集，并考虑到演员生病了
things that communicate just through
只是通过交流的东西
messages it's a perfect abstraction to
消息，它是一个完美的抽象
also scale out so you will you will be
也可以向外扩展，这样您就可以了
able to put those actors on different
能够将那些演员放在不同的位置
nodes and they will still communicate
节点，它们仍然可以通信
through messages so the the way they
通过消息，所以他们的方式
communicate will be the same the
沟通将是相同的
abstraction will be the same of course
当然，抽象将是相同的
there will be differences for example
例如会有差异
you need to handle that the latency and
您需要处理延迟和
response times are very different on a
响应时间在一个
local node compared to the remote node
本地节点与远程节点的比较
but this is a really nice kind of
但这是一种非常好的
I would almost say the killer app of
我几乎会说
akka
阿卡
another thing is extremes which is a
另一件事是极端，这是
synchronous and back pressured streams
同步和背压流
framework for building streaming graphs
构建流图的框架
for processing data of different kinds
用于处理各种数据
and this is also kind of
这也是
the core of the HTTP server which is has
HTTP服务器的核心是
been written for akka okay so if if you
是为阿卡写的好吧，如果你
after this long and tedious babbling
经过漫长而乏味的
from me feel like this is something you
从我那里感觉到这是你的事
would like to look closer at then we
想要仔细看看，然后我们
have some pretty extensive talks that
有一些相当广泛的谈话
might be interesting to start with and
从开始可能会很有趣
that is you can find that I use slash
那就是你可以发现我用斜杠
dogs we have a very friendly community
狗，我们有一个非常友好的社区
with a killer Channel and the mailing
带有杀手级频道和邮件
list which are really good places to ask
列出真正要问的好地方
questions and get help and this live
问题并获得帮助，此活动
coding sources will be available shortly
编码源将很快可用
after the webinar at this github
在这个github上的网络研讨会之后
repository listed ok so I think that
仓库列出的好，所以我认为
would be time for maybe questions done
是时候解决问题了
yeah thank you join for comprehensive
是的，谢谢您的全面参与
introduction it was really interesting
介绍真的很有趣
and yeah we are slightly ran out of time
是的，我们时间有点用光了
but still have quite still have time for
但仍然有足够的时间
some questions I'll read them and yeah
我会读一些问题，是的
so you can answer the first question is
所以你可以回答的第一个问题是
there a way to create an actor without
没有一种方法可以创建一个演员
having to extend the abstract actor no
不必扩展抽象演员
so this is why I mentioned that you
所以这就是为什么我提到你
should model your domain specific things
应该为您的领域建模
with your regular kind of
与你常规的
object-oriented toolkits and wrap those
面向对象的工具箱并将其包装
with actors rather than maybe tightly
与演员在一起而不是紧紧地
coupled the logic to the actors ok
将逻辑与演员耦合好
thanks and the next question I try to
谢谢，我尝试下一个问题
implement an actor in Scala I find it's
在Scala中实现一个演员，我发现
easy just to override receive method and
只需重写接收方法即可，并且
pass methods to cube by using the
通过使用方法将方法传递给多维数据集
exclamation mark however in Java it's a
感叹号，但是在Java中
little complicated to write and
有点复杂写和
understand please let us know your view
了解请告诉我们您的看法
on that
在那
yeah okay so Scala gives us a few more
是的，Scala还给了我们更多
tools to make the API is to interact
使API进行交互的工具
with actors minimal in a very concise
与演员在一起非常简洁
which isn't possible with Java on the
这在Java上是不可能的
other hand with Java everything is very
另一方面，Java的一切都非常
explicit and could probably be easier to
明确的，可能更容易
follow and I mean it's a it's a matter
跟着，我的意思是这是一个问题
of taste with languages so I think it
语言的品味，所以我认为
would be hard to make it more minimal
很难使它最小化
api's for job and then they currently
api的工作，然后他们目前
are of course there are cases corner
当然有案例
cases some sort of edges but but in
情况下有些边缘，但在
general I it is just a bit more verbose
一般我只是有点冗长
in Java and that might be something you
在Java中，那可能就是你
like or it might be something that you
喜欢或它可能是你的东西
don't like so you have the choice
不喜欢，所以您可以选择
between Java and Scala and Watauga okay
Java与Scala和Watauga之间的关系还可以
and the next question what is the scope
下一个问题是什么范围
of an actor system how to access an egg
系统的访问方法
an actor of an actor system from another
来自另一个演员系统的演员
Jairam process so if you want to
Jairam流程，所以如果您想
interact between systems of different
不同系统之间的交互
JVMs there are a few options so one
JVM有几种选择，因此一种
option is when you want to build a
选项是当您想要构建一个
distributed system right you want to
您想要的分布式系统权限
build something that is one application
构建一个应用程序
that covers more than a single JVM and
涵盖了不止一个JVM
in this case it is clustering which I
在这种情况下，我正在聚类
mentioned clustering and like I can
提到聚类，就像我可以
remote thing was definitely clustering
远程的东西肯定是聚集的
in the other case it's just two systems
在其他情况下，这只是两个系统
that are interacting through some
通过一些互动
whatever protocol you would like so for
您想要的任何协议
example you would write maybe a mail
例如，您可能会写一封邮件
client and a mail server then you will
客户端和邮件服务器，那么您将
communicate through an
通过沟通
application-specific protocol rather
特定于应用程序的协议
than doing something that is akka
比做些客气的事
specific even though you might write
具体的，即使你可能写
both sides of the communication part in
双方沟通的一部分
in there in that with an actor system
在那个演员系统中
okay
好的
moving to next question the question is
转到下一个问题，问题是
about the first sample
关于第一个样本
so basically the sample app shows that
所以基本上示例应用程序显示
the messages will be processed in some
邮件将在某些情况下进行处理
kind of queue right
排队的权利
meaning that each message will be
意味着每条消息都会
processed until it finished and then the
处理直到完成，然后
actor will process the next message is
演员将处理下一条消息是
it correct understanding yes this is
它正确的理解是的，这是
exactly correct
完全正确
so there is a single threaded illusion
所以有一个单线错觉
inside of the actor even though it might
演员内部，即使可能
move between the threads of the of the
在的线程之间移动
dispatcher it's when you look at it they
调度员，当你看着它
will seem to be running in a single
似乎会一次运行
thread one message at a time yeah and
一次处理一条消息，是的，
next question is it is it recommended to
下一个问题是建议
access is it advisable to access the
建议您访问
database from an actor shouldn't it
演员的数据库不应该吗
shouldn't all the actions performed by
不应由
an actor be a synchronous so this is
演员是同步演员，所以这是
exactly what I was talking about in the
正是我在讲的
end you can do blocking stuff in actors
最后你可以阻止演员中的东西
but you need to make sure that you
但您需要确保自己
isolate them onto a specific thread pool
将它们隔离到特定的线程池中
based dispatcher so that they don't
基于调度程序，这样他们就不会
affect the rest of the system but I mean
影响系统的其余部分，但我的意思是
if you are allowed to have 8 connections
如果允许您有8个连接
to your database then it doesn't doesn't
到您的数据库，那么它就不会
matter if you have you know you could
不管你是否知道你可以
represent that with 8 actors and it will
代表8位演员，它将
fit perfectly with what you can actually
完全符合您的实际需求
do in your system ok and next question
在您的系统中做好，下一个问题
we have a built-in actor system and play
我们有一个内置的演员系统，可以玩
framework my question is while creating
框架我的问题是在创建时
actors shall we use the default one or
演员，我们应该使用默认值之一还是
create our own actor system and is it
创建我们自己的演员系统
useful to create more than one actor
有助于创建多个演员
system ok so my my my current knowledge
系统好，所以我是我目前的知识
of play is a bit rusty but there used to
游戏有点生锈，但过去
be a separate kind of actor system for
成为一种独立的参与者系统
play and one for kind of the user
玩和一种用户
application I'm not sure if it is like
应用程序我不确定是否喜欢
this anymore so this was probably
这样了，所以这可能是
because at some point they wanted to
因为在某些时候他们想
make
使
they were isolated from the user logic
它们与用户逻辑隔离
very unsure if it's still like this in
非常不确定它是否仍然像这样
some cases it might be useful to create
在某些情况下，创建可能会有用
more than one but in general normal
多个，但总体正常
application wouldn't want wouldn't need
应用程序不需要
more than one and the reason for this is
不止一个，原因是
that each actor system will occupy
每个参与者系统将占据的位置
resources and they will create thread
资源，它们将创建线程
pools and so it's a relatively heavy
游泳池，所以这是一个相对沉重的
construct you wouldn't want lots and
构造你不想要很多东西
lots of it and next question
很多和下一个问题
is it is it possible to use akka in g:w
是否有可能在g：w中使用akka
application server I have heard about
我听说过的应用服务器
people doing this so the tricky part is
人们这样做，所以棘手的部分是
that the thread pool that akka manages
由akka管理的线程池
how that kind of if the Java EE
Java EE怎么样
application server allows things to have
应用服务器允许事物具有
their own threads I think it's a bit
他们自己的线程，我认为这有点
vendor dependent like in general which
一般来说，取决于供应商
are way you're not allowed to start
是不允许您开始的方式
threads but you could probably with
线程，但你可能可以
vendor specific extensions create
供应商特定的扩展创建
something that will create an actor
可以创造演员的东西
system that you can then use as a
您可以将其用作
resource inside of your application
应用程序内部的资源
server so it depends okay and now a
服务器，所以这取决于好的，现在
question whether it possible to inject a
质疑是否有可能注入
spring bean to an actor yeah it requires
春豆给演员，是的，它需要
some special some special hoops but
一些特殊的一些特殊的箍，但
there is examples in the documentation
文档中有示例
even I think for integrating with spring
甚至我认为与春天融为一体
okay now if you have a huge number of
好吧，如果您有大量的
factors how the actor system creates
影响角色系统创建方式的因素
them in parallel when do you know when
他们并行何时知道何时
this when the system is ready to handle
当系统准备好处理时
messages if the actors are dependent on
演员是否依赖的消息
each other
彼此
okay so you can see you can think of
好的，所以您可以看到您可以想到的
this question in different ways one way
这个问题以不同的方式
is that if you have the actor if it's
那是如果你有演员的话
perfectly valid to send it messages even
完全有效，甚至可以向其发送消息
though it's not ready so those will just
虽然还没有准备好，所以那些会
be queued up and then when the actor is
排队，然后当演员
actually started so that's happening as
实际上开始，所以发生
synchronously then you call actor off it
同步，然后将其关闭
was and it returns it doesn't mean that
过去，它返回并不意味着
the actor has be started already just
演员已经开始了
means that but you will get the nectar
意味着，但你会得到花蜜
of which you can send messages to so if
您可以向其中发送消息，如果
you have a huge and complex kind of
你有一个巨大而复杂的
graph which you need to get in some
您需要进入的图表
specific state before you can start have
开始之前的特定状态
it start processing messages then you
它开始处理消息，然后您
need to signal that somehow so in your
需要以某种方式告知您
entry points you will have have to have
您必须拥有的入口点
some kind of protocol which you get from
您从中获得的某种协议
all these things that needs to be
所有这些都需要
started and initialized so in general I
开始并初始化，所以一般来说我
would say try to use like dependency
会说尝试使用像依赖
injection in in the form of not in the
注射形式不是
form of a framework but in the form of
框架形式，但形式为
if an actor needs to talk to another
如果演员需要和另一个人说话
actor pass the actor ref to it this way
演员以这种方式将演员引用传递给它
you will essentially have to create the
您基本上必须创建
actors in an order that matches the
演员的顺序与
dependencies and you will not have to
依赖关系，您将不必
kind of keep any kind of protocol to
保持某种协议以
synchronize this you will you will
同步这个，你会的
essentially be able to start as soon as
基本上能够尽快启动
you have created all of the actors okay
您已经创建了所有演员
moving put it could you recommend any
移动把它你可以推荐任何
books about akka not from the top of my
关于akka的书不是来自我的
head but there is a bunch and there is a
头，但有一束，有一个
list in the documentation that I would
在文档中列出我会
recommend you to look at okay the
建议你看看好吗
question is there way to have tell and
问题是有办法告诉和
forward methods when actor rafts
演员筏时的前进方法
be typesafe there is a comment next to
是类型安全的，旁边有一个评论
the question probably not because they
问题可能不是因为他们
accepted types of messages where an
接受的邮件类型
actor can change over time yeah so this
演员可以随时间改变是的，所以这
is definitely kind of part of the
绝对是其中的一部分
problem why it's really hard that the
问题，为什么真的很难
behavior can change but also like one of
行为可以改变，但也可以像
the really neat things with actresses
女星真正整洁的事情
that you can just put another actor in
你可以放一个演员
between you keep the protocol you're the
你之间保持协议，你是
sending actor doesn't know anything
派演员一无所知
about it
关于它
but you just snuck in this cashing actor
但是你只是偷偷换了这个赚钱的演员
in between which will respond to some
在这两者之间会回应一些
messages but not others this is also
消息，但没有其他，这也是
something that is hard to represent you
很难代表你的东西
know typesafe matter however there is a
知道类型安全问题，但是有一个
sub-module of actor which which is being
演员的子模块
under development which is called akka
正在开发中，称为akka
typed which if it's kind of it's not
键入如果不是的话
ready anytime soon but there is work
随时准备，但有工作
being done on on a year and a way to do
在一年的时间里做
typesafe actors I'm not sure if this
类型安全演员，我不确定这是否
will be possible to represent with with
将有可能用
Java API so in the future we will see
Java API，因此将来我们会看到
where it kind of lands that is something
它在什么地方着陆
to look into if you're interested in
调查您是否有兴趣
this topic yeah and knowing next
这个话题是的，接下来知道
question not really sure I get the
问题不是很确定我得到了
meaning of the question still I'll read
问题的含义我仍然会读
that any blocking routine has to be
任何阻塞程序必须
placed in a different thread pool so as
放置在不同的线程池中，以便
always with software it depends but it's
总是与软件有关，但这取决于
a good rule of thumb that you should try
一个好的经验法则，你应该尝试
to isolate the blocking stuff onto a
将阻塞物隔离到
separate thread pool of course you can
当然可以使用单独的线程池
have a separate thread pool for all the
有一个单独的线程池
i/o for example all the blocking i/o
I / O，例如所有阻塞的I / O
even though you have different actors
即使你有不同的演员
doing different blocking i/o so this is
做不同的阻塞I / O，所以这是
kind of a something you have to think
有点你必须要思考的东西
about with your own system how it will
关于您自己的系统
affect it which parts will stop other
影响它哪些部分将停止其他
from processing and if that's sensible
从处理，如果这是明智的
or not yep now you mentioned better deep
还是不，现在你提到更好的深
here our kiss then white hair our keys
这是我们的吻，然后是白发，是我们的钥匙
is it just because there's a supervision
只是因为有监督
or something else yeah absolutely about
或其他绝对有关的东西
supervision that you can separate parts
监督您可以分开零件
of your system that shouldn't kind of
您的系统中不应
affect the other parts when they break
断裂时影响其他部分
and you push the dangerous work
而你推动了危险的工作
downwards in hierarchy right because
向下层次结构权利，因为
because the error comes upwards and the
因为错误上升，并且
smaller parts you have that will fail
您拥有的较小零件将失败
the the smaller parts you can restart
您可以重新启动的较小零件
without affecting other parts of the
而不影响其他部分
system okay
系统还可以
in the current version of our con is it
在我们的骗局的当前版本中
considerate a good practice to use our
考虑使用我们的良好做法
core futures and the patterns ask
核心期货和格局问
parenting okay so in the current version
育儿还可以，所以在当前版本中
of vodka which is to 4.10 from Java then
从Java到4.10的伏特加
you will probably not use future so much
你可能不会用太多的未来
but instead the completion stage class
而是完成阶段课程
which is essentially the same thing as
这基本上与
futures futures is a data structure from
期货期货是一种来自
from Scala and the completion stage is
来自Scala，完成阶段是
something that does the same on the Java
在Java上做同样的事情
side the ask pattern I didn't really
我不是真正的询问模式
mention during the talk but it's it's a
在谈话中提到，但这是一个
way to encapsulate a query so if you
封装查询的方式，如果您
have a protocol which contains a query
有一个包含查询的协议
message and then a response message and
消息，然后是响应消息，以及
you want to kind of tie those together
你想把那些绑在一起
somehow with a timeout because you don't
由于某种原因超时
want to wait infinitely for response and
想无限地等待响应，
then you want to kind of act on the
那么您想对
response if you're outside of an actor I
如果您不在演员中，我会回应
need to query it then definitely there
需要查询然后肯定在那里
is this isn't really another option then
这真的不是另一种选择吗
ask if you're inside of an actor there
询问您是否在演员里面
are a few different options but parents
有几个不同的选择，但父母
the task is pretty good note however
这项任务是非常好的笔记
this is a special special patterns
这是一个特殊的特殊模式
don't ask for Java 8 which is called CS
不要要求称为CS的Java 8
patterns don't ask I think which will
模式不问我想哪个会
return on a completion stage and you
回到完成阶段，您
will not have to kind of 12 into Scala
不必在Scala中输入12
the ice to do stuff from Java okay next
可以做Java的东西了
question how does actor how does act
问题演员如何表现
integrate with message and cues like
与消息和提示集成
RabbitMQ with this advisable so there is
RabbitMQ与这个建议，所以有
open source project connector that
开源项目连接器
connects to rabbitmq with with actors so
与演员连接到rabbitmq，因此
you will get messages from the mq like
您将收到来自MQ的消息，例如
messages inside of your actor system
actor系统内部的消息
it's very nice I have used it before I
很好，我之前用过
joined my spotlight band there might it
参加我的聚光灯乐队
might be a better fit to look at
可能更适合看
extremes with extremes connectors
带极端连接器的极端
because they kind of match how a message
因为他们匹配一条消息
queue work a bit better let you kind of
排队工作更好一点，让您有点
back pressure and not consume too many
背压，不要消耗太多
messages from the message queue compared
比较消息队列中的消息
to how many you can process and your
可以处理多少，您的
throughput ok and written next question
吞吐量确定并写下下一个问题
I'll be working on the custom akka
我将研究自定义akka
system which has some unknown who now
现在有一些未知的人的系统
flows what we could observe was that
流动我们可以观察到的是
some actors crashed and we lost their
一些演员坠毁，我们失去了他们的
state what are the first parts we should
陈述我们应该做的第一部分
check ok so if if there are actors that
检查确定，以便确定是否有演员
crash and then they will get restarted
崩溃，然后它们将重新启动
because that's the default supervision
因为这是默认的监管
strategy so that is look at their parent
策略，那就是看他们的父母
actor and how it will supervise its
演员及其监督方式
children think about if you should have
孩子们想想你是否应该
different behavior or if if you can push
不同的行为或是否可以推动
the dangerous thing that caused them to
导致他们死亡的危险
crash lower down
崩溃向下
in the hierarchy okay good is it
在层次结构中，好吗？
possible to communicate across VM or
可以跨VM通信或
host yeah this is again depends on what
主持人，这又取决于什么
you want to do if you want to build a
如果你想建立一个你想做的
distributed system new you will use akka
您将使用akka的分布式系统新
cluster or accurate mooting I would say
我会说群集或准确的模拟
akka cluster if you want to build for
akka集群，如果您要构建
example client-server system of some
某些示例客户端-服务器系统
kind then it will just be about defining
善良的话，那就只是定义
a protocol to use over TCP for example
例如在TCP上使用的协议
so then either side won't really know
所以任何一方都不会真正知道
that the other side is it's an actor
另一面是演员
system but it will be like a separate
系统，但它将像一个单独的
client and server implementation yeah
客户端和服务器实施是的
next question do you plan to create
您打算创建下一个问题
webinar about ARCA classroom so I think
关于ARCA教室的网络研讨会，我想
this might be a question to you a bit
这可能是您的一个问题
maybe yeah sure why not yeah sure do
也许是的，为什么不呢？
actor support reactive spec that is back
演员支持的反应式规格又回来了
pressure enabled so I'm gonna guess that
启用压力，所以我会猜测
with reactive spec what this meant is
使用反应式规范这是什么意思
reactive stream specifications so this
反应流规格因此
is what our cast reims is it's an
这是我们的主观建议是
implementation of the reactive stream
反应流的实现
specification actors in themselves
规范参与者本身
doesn't do back pressure so you will
不会背压，所以您会
have to define define your actor system
必须定义定义演员系统
to to deal with if you have a slower
如果你慢一点要处理
slower throughput then you have an
吞吐速度较慢，那么您有
inflow of messages for example you will
消息流入，例如，您将
have to think about this when you design
设计时必须考虑一下
your actors yep and when and why to go
您的演员是，何时以及为何去
for arc route routing can you elaborate
弧线路由可以详细说明吗
its significance in a simple way yeah so
它的意义很简单，是的，所以
what I didn't look closer at in the fine
我没仔细看过的东西
sample of the the LiveCode or the the
LiveCode或
prepared sample of the life coat was
救生衣的准备好的样品是
that I was actually using routing so
我实际上是在使用路由
what routing is is something where you
什么路由是你所需要的东西
can create four instances of an actor
可以创建一个actor的四个实例
for example and you will essentially
例如，您将本质上
have an actor F to send messages to you
让演员F向您发送消息
don't you are kind of deferred how
难道你有点推迟
messages are distributed between those
消息在那些之间分配
four actors so there's different
四个演员，所以有不同
different kind of routing for example
例如，不同类型的路由
you could have done a round round-robin
你本可以做一个循环赛
router which will for every new message
路由器将为每个新消息
that comes in it will just pick the next
进来的只是选择下一个
actors and then and then when it reaches
演员，然后当它到达时
the end of the list they will start over
列表的结尾，他们将从头开始
start over with the first one so this is
从第一个开始，所以这是
for example a way to distribute
例如一种分配方式
processing over all your course you
处理您所有的课程
create as many actors as you have course
根据您的课程创建尽可能多的演员
and then you just use this router to to
然后您只需使用此路由器即可
distribute the work between the menus
在菜单之间分配工作
and the messages okay good I think
而且消息还可以，我认为
that's that's it we have no more
就是这样，我们没有了
questions but in case someone has more
问题，但如果有人有更多
questions just feel free to ask them in
问题随便问
Twitter were when we publish the
Twitter是我们发布
recording you can post them as comments
录制您可以将其发布为评论
so we'll try to answer all them so thank
所以我们将尝试回答所有问题，谢谢
you for your time and for questions and
您的时间和问题，以及
John of course thank you for the
约翰当然感谢您
presentation thank you okay see everyone
演示文稿，谢谢，好吧，大家见
take care and have a good day good bye
保重，祝你有美好的一天再见
bye bye
再见